Bring protection.
A Million Ways to Die in the West is a comedy,
western film directed by Seth MacFarlane.
As a cowardly farmer begins to fall for the mysterious new woman in town, he must put his new-found
courage to the test when her husband, a notorious gun-slinger, announces his arrival.
Albert, played by Seth MacFarlane.
Anna, played by Charlize Theron.
Louise, played by Amanda Seyfried.
Clinch, played by Liam Neeson.
Edward, played by Giovanni Ribisi.
Foy, played by Neil Patrick Harris.
A Million Ways to Die in the West is a 2014 American Western comedy film directed by
Seth MacFarlane and written by MacFarlane, Alec Sulkin and Wellesley Wild.
The film features an ensemble cast including MacFarlane, Charlize Theron, Amanda Seyfried,
Neil Patrick Harris, Giovanni Ribisi, Sarah Silverman, and Liam Neeson.
The film follows a cowardly frontiersman who gains courage with the help of a female gunfighter and
must use his newfound skills in a confrontation with her villainous outlaw husband.
Development began while MacFarlane and co-writers Sulkin and Wild were
watching Western movies during the development of Ted (2012).
Casting was done between December 2012 and March 2013.
Filming began on May 6, 2013, in various locations in New Mexico including
Albuquerque and Santa Fe, and it concluded on August 9 that year.
Joel McNeely composed the score.
The film was released on May 30, 2014, in the United States,
and distributed worldwide by Universal Pictures.
The film received mixed to negative reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of gunslinger, farmer, wild west,
aftercreditsstinger, duringcreditsstinger.
The tone is lighthearted.